Finding Aid for the J. Paul Getty Ranch House Records, 1921, 1945-1960s, 1975-1976, 1980s, 1999-2007, and undated IA20021
Institutional Records and Archives
Ranch House records
1921, 1945-1960s, 1975-1976, 1980s, 1999-2007, undated
Institutional Records and Archives
Fredericksen, Burton B.
Claud Beelman & Associates
Bramlett, Norris (Cagle Norris)
Garrett, Stephen
John Byers, Architect
Gruen Associates
Getty, J. Paul (Jean Paul), 1892-1976
Vogler, Eileen
J. Paul Getty Trust
IA20021
21.6 Linear Feet (6 boxes, 1 binder, 15 flat files)
Records consist of correspondence, memoranda, reports, legal documents, brochures, clippings, architectural drawings, and photographs, 1921, 1945-1960s, 1975-1976, 1980s, 1999-2007 and undated, that describe the history of, and planned and executed alterations and additions to, J. Paul Getty's Ranch House in Malibu, California. Also included is some administrative material relating to Ranch House personnel.
Acquisition Information
The records in this finding aid originated in accession nos. 1986.IA.01 boxes 46, 67, 86, 129 and 138 (transferred to the Institutional Archives by the J. Paul Getty Museum); 1986.IA.19 (transferred to the Institutional Archives by the J. Paul Getty Museum); 1986.IA.20 (transferred to the Institutional Archives by the J. Paul Getty Trust); 1986.IA.27 (transferred to the Institutional Archives by Don Hull, Department of Photography, J. Paul Getty Museum); 1986.IA.39; 2003.IA.10; 2004.IA.13 (transferred to the Institutional Archives by Barbara Whitney, J. Paul Getty Museum); and 2010.IA.04 (transferred to the Institutional Archives by the Getty Research Institute, Villa Librarian, Barbara Furbush).
Please note that the material in accession 1986.IA.01 has been assigned a new accession number, 1986.IA.50, for purposes of providing better administrative control.
Restrictions on Access
The records described in accessions 1986.IA.19, 1986.IA.20, 1986.IA.27, 1986.IA.39, 2003.IA.10, 2004.IA.13, and 2010.IA.04 are available for use by qualified researchers.
The records in accession 1986.IA.50, subject to review for permanently closed information, are open to qualified researchers. Requests for access will be reviewed on a case-by-case basis.
The following types of records are permanently closed: records containing personal information, records that compromise security or operations, legal communications, legal work product, and records related to donors. The J. Paul Getty Trust reserves the right to restrict access to any records held by the Institutional Archives.
Scope and Content of Collection
Records consist of correspondence, memoranda, reports, contracts, permits, invoices, brochures, clippings, blueline prints, blueprints, architectural drawings, and photographs, 1921, 1945-1960s, 1975-1976, 1980s, 1999-2007 and undated, that describe J. Paul Getty's Ranch House in Malibu, California and the alterations made to it over time.
The history of the building is summarized in the Historic American Buildings Survey (HABS) documentation, which provides background information on the Ranch House, including its significance, history, architecture, a site description, maps, plans, and photographs. The renovation and administration records contain information about work undertaken in the 1950s to expand gallery space by the Los Angeles architectural firm of Claud Beelman & Associates; the financial administration of the project was handled by Norris Bramlett. The records describe preparations for a proposed visit by Getty to the Ranch in the 1960s through copies of correspondence between Getty, Norris Bramlett, and Eileen Vogler, a long-time Getty employee. In March 1973, the Trustees passed a resolution requesting that Getty authorize construction of an access road to the Museum, and the records contain information about the costs and planning of this project. In the late 1970s the Trustees explored the possibility of expanding the Ranch House for more gallery space. Gruen Associates was retained to advise the Trustees, and their report, related correspondence, and a geological investigation is included in the records. Also included in the records are two inventories of the collections conducted in the late 1970s (the purpose of these inventories is unknown); and letters from Stephen Garrett, Museum Director, to the Ranch House staff discussing their transfer to museum staff. The records also include architectural drawings, a large portion of which relate to the renovation of the property by the architect John Byers, begun in 1946, for both residential and art gallery spaces in the house. The photographs included in the records depict the Ranch House before, during, and after renovation.
Organization
These records are organized in four series:
Series I. Historic American Buildings Survey documentation, 1999, 2001
Series II. Renovation and administration records, 1954-1982
Series III. Architectural drawings, 1921, 1945-1951, 1975-1976 and undated
Series IV. Photographs and subject file, circa 1950s-1960s, 1980s, 1999-2007, and undated.
Administrative History
Located just off the Pacific Coast Highway about a mile north of Sunset Boulevard on 64-acres near Malibu, California, the Ranch House became the site for the original J. Paul Getty Museum. Purchased by J. Paul Getty in 1945 from Claude I. Parker for the sum of $250,000, the property was originally part of an early nineteenth century Spanish land grant. In the 1920s Parker, a Los Angeles attorney, purchased a portion of the property from Perfecto Marquez, a descendent of one of the area's original settlers. Parker constructed a house, the core of the extant Ranch House, and several outbuildings. Getty made additions and major alterations to the Ranch House, including the addition of a second floor to the eastern portion, creating the house that stands on the property today.
At the time Getty purchased the Malibu property, he already owned a house in Santa Monica, at 270 Ocean Front, and therefore only occupied the Ranch House on weekends. In 1946, Getty commissioned the Los Angeles architect John Byers to design additions to the Ranch House, primarily to house Getty's art collections, including a second floor at the eastern end, the Louis XV Room, the Hallway Gallery, the Louis XVI Room, the Small Antiquities Room, and the Courtyard. In 1953 Mr. Getty established the J. Paul Getty Museum Trust and in 1954 opened the gallery spaces at the eastern end of the house to the public. In 1957, a new gallery wing along the west edge of the courtyard was added by the Los Angeles-based architectural firm Claud Beelman and Associates to house Getty's expanding collection of antiquities. The eastern end of the house continued to function as the museum until 1974 (with about 6,000 square feet of exhibition space), when the Getty Villa was completed and opened as the primary repository for Mr. Getty's art collection.
With the Getty Villa acting as the new museum quarters, portions of the Ranch House were altered to accommodate museum administration and conservation laboratories. Major modifications to the interior of the Ranch House, including the conversion of gallery spaces to conservation, laboratory and office spaces. The construction of new buildings in the courtyard area were carried out during the mid-1980s.
The Ranch House was the subject of a 2001 Historic American Buildings Survey report.
[Adapted from "Historic American Buildings Survey Documentation."]
Clippings (information artifacts); Architecture -- California -- Los Angeles; Contracts; Blueline prints; Correspondence; Memorandums; Blueprints (reprographic copies); Museum buildings -- California; Ranch houses; Reports; Dwellings -- California -- Los Angeles, 1940-1950; Brochures; Invoices; Permits; Architectural drawings (visual works); Photographs
- Historic American Buildings Survey documentation, 1999; 2001,; undated; Series I.; 0.4 Linear Feet (1 box)
  Arrangement
  These records are arranged in the order found within the original accession.
  Scope and Contents note
  Records consist of a report and black and white photographs and negatives, 1999, 2001, and undated, of the Historic American Buildings Survey (HABS) conducted for the J. Paul Getty Ranch House by PCR Services Corporation, Santa Monica, California. The report provides a HABS number, and physical description, significance, historical information, architectural information, site description, a bibliography, project information, maps and plans, and an index to the photographs of the Ranch House. Also included are photocopies of half of the photographs.
  - Historic American Buildings Survey Documentation report, September 2001 (Box 2003.IA.10-1, Folder 1)
  - [40 black and white photographs with captions], September 2001; [3 files] (Box 2003.IA.10-1, Folder 4-6)
  - [40 original negatives], September 2001; [2 files] (Box 2003.IA.10-1, Folder 7-8)
  - Index to photographs, September 2001 (Box 2003.IA.10-1, Folder 2)
  - Photocopies of images, September 2001 (Box 2003.IA.10-1, Folder 3)
  - [Negatives and contact sheets], November 1999; [3 sheets of negatives; 2 copies of each contact sheet.] (Box 2003.IA.10-1, Folder 9)
  - [21 color photographs], undated (Box 2003.IA.10-1, Folder 10)
  - [28 black and white negatives], September 2001 (Box 2003.IA.10-1, Folder 11)
    General note
    [Not used in the report.]
  - [28 black and white photographs], September 2001 (Box 2003.IA.10-1, Folder 12-14)
    [3 sets; one with captions on white paper, one with captions on brown paper, one with no captions. Not used in the report.]
- Renovation and administration records, 1954-1982; Series II.; 5.4 Linear Feet (3 boxes, 1 flat file)
  These records are arranged by subject/project.
  Records consist of correspondence, memoranda, reports, contracts, permits, invoices, brochures, and clippings, 1954-1982, pertaining to J. Paul Getty's Ranch House in Malibu, California. The records describe additions and alterations to the Ranch House, and administrative matters pertaining to its maintenance and upkeep.
  The records contain information about work undertaken to expand gallery space by the Los Angeles architectural firm of Claud Beelman & Associates, and P.J. Walker Company Builders, in the 1950s; the financial administration of the project was handled by Norris Bramlett. The records describe preparations for a proposed visit by Getty to the Ranch in the 1960s through copies of correspondence between Getty, Norris Bramlett, and Eileen Vogler, interior designer. In March 1973, the Trustees passed a resolution requesting that Getty authorize construction of an access road to the Museum, along Los Liones Road. The records contain detailed information about the costs and planning of this project. In the late 1970s the Trustees explored the possibility of expanding the Ranch House for more gallery space. Gruen Associates was retained to advise the Trustees; their report, related correspondence, and a geological investigation conducted by LeRoy Crandall & Associates is included in the records. The records also contain two inventories of the collections conducted in the late 1970s (the purpose of these inventories is unknown); and letters from Stephen Garrett, Museum Director, to the Ranch House staff discussing their transfer to museum staff.
  - Clippings re: museum, letters re: Collector's Choice, 1954-1956 (Box 1986.IA.50-1, Folder 3)
  - Claud Beelman and Associates addition:
    - Miscellaneous permits and licenses, 1954; 1957,; 1964 (Box 1986.IA.50-1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, invoices, notes re: interior furnishings, smoke detections, 1954; 1957-1958 (Box 1986.IA.50-1, Folder 2)
    - Contract with Walker Co., 1957-1958; [2 files] (Box 1986.IA.50-1, Folder 4-5)
    - Building addition, museum wing, 1957 (Box 1986.IA.50-1, Folder 6)
    - Specifications for alterations and additions, April 16, 1957; [2 files] (Box 1986.IA.50-1, Folder 7-8)
  - J. Paul Getty's possible return:
    - Correspondence re: Ranch House repairs and furnishings, 1966-1969 (Box 1986.IA.50-1, Folder 9)
    - Brochures, price lists for furnishings, circa 1969 (Box 1986.IA.50-1, Folder 10)
    - Invoices/expenses for J. Paul Getty's possible return to Ranch House, 1969-1970; [3 files] (Box 1986.IA.50-1, Folder 11-13)
    - To do lists, letters, tallies re: purchases for J. Paul Getty's possible return, 1969-1970 (Box 1986.IA.50-1, Folder 14)
    - Lists of items received, 1970 (Box 1986.IA.50-1, Folder 15)
    - Purchases and prices, 1970 (Box 1986.IA.50-1, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous notes, letters re: furnishings, 1970 (Box 1986.IA.50-1, Folder 17)
  - Los Liones Road (north access):
    - Invoices, 1973-1974 (Box 1986.IA.50-1, Folder 18)
    - Grading permit surety bond, 1973 (Box 1986.IA.50-1, Folder 19)
    - Letters re: geologic inspection, 1973 (Box 1986.IA.50-1, Folder 20)
    - Insurance, 1973 (Box 1986.IA.50-1, Folder 21)
    - Costs, 1973-1974 (Box 1986.IA.50-2, Folder 1)
    - Stabilization, 1973 (Box 1986.IA.50-2, Folder 2)
    - Trustee request re: road, 1973 (Box 1986.IA.50-2, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, permits, reports, 1972-1973 (Box 1986.IA.50-2, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, permits, reports, 1969-1972 (Box 1986.IA.50-2, Folder 5)
      [Vicinity map, easement map, and Golden Land Investment Corp. map rehoused into Flat file 4.]
  - Feasibility study:
    - Feasibility study, ranch (Gruen), correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 1986.IA.50-2, Folder 6)
    - Gruen Associates proposal letter, 1978 (Box 1986.IA.50-2, Folder 7)
    - Gruen feasibility study, 1979 (Box 1986.IA.50-2, Folder 8)
    - Preliminary geologic investigation report, 1979 (Box 1986.IA.50-2, Folder 9)
      [Aerial photograph, topographic maps, and geologic maps rehoused into Box 3.]
    - Feasibility study, Ranch—clipping re: Santa Monica Mountains, June 1979 (Box 1986.IA.50-2, Folder 10)
    - Victor Gruen death announcement, 1980 (Box 1986.IA.50-2, Folder 11)
  - Administration:
    - Inventory re: ranch, September 15, 1976 (Box 1986.IA.50-2, Folder 12)
    - Inventory of art object, furniture, furnishings, May 14, 1979 (Box 1986.IA.50-2, Folder 13)
    - Letters, memos re: Ranch House staff, 1979; undated (Box 1986.IA.50-2, Folder 14)
    - Ranch House furniture gifts—letters, memos, 1982 (Box 1986.IA.50-2, Folder 15)
- Architectural drawings, 1921; 1945-1951,; 1975-1976,; undated; Series III.; 15 Linear Feet (15 flat files)
  These records are generally arranged by job and chronologically, and when undated, in the order found within the original accession.
  Records consist of blueprints, blueline prints, and architectural drawings, 1921, 1945-1951, 1975-1976 and undated, from various J. Paul Getty Ranch House renovation and alteration projects. A large portion of this material relates to the renovation of the property by the architect John Byers of Santa Monica, begun in 1946, for both residential and art gallery spaces in the house, and a 1950 art gallery renovation. In some cases the purpose, or jobs, for which drawings were created is unknown.
  - "Topographic map of 27.325 acres in Canada Sentimento, Rancho Boca de Santa Monica for Claude Parker. Surveyed November 1921. Wilkie Woodward Engineer,", [2 copies.] (Flatfile 2004.IA.13-2)
  - John Byers' renovations:
    - "Art Gallery. Donald R. Warren Engineer, floor plans and sections,", September 7, 1945 (Flatfile 2004.IA.13-1)
    - "Art Gallery. Donald R. Warren Engineer, sections,", September 7, 1945 (Flatfile 2004.IA.13-1)
    - "Art Gallery. Donald R. Warren Engineer, hip beam framing,", September 7, 1945 (Flatfile 2004.IA.13-1)
    - "Art Gallery for J. Paul Getty. Roosevelt Blvd. John Byers, Architect. 1st floor plan,", October 10, 1945 (Flatfile 2004.IA.13-1)
    - "Art Gallery for J. Paul Getty. Roosevelt Blvd. John Byers, Architect. 2nd floor plan,", October 10, 1945 (Flatfile 2004.IA.13-1)
    - "Art Gallery for J. Paul Getty. Roosevelt Blvd. John Byers, Architect. front elevation,", October 10, 1945 (Flatfile 2004.IA.13-1)
    - "Art Gallery for J. Paul Getty. Roosevelt Blvd. John Byers, Architect. rear elevation,", October 10, 1945 (Flatfile 2004.IA.13-1)
    - "Art Gallery for J. Paul Getty. Roosevelt Blvd. John Byers, Architect. interior sections,", October 10, 1945 (Flatfile 2004.IA.13-1)
    - "Art Gallery for J. Paul Getty. Roosevelt Blvd. John Byers, Architect,", October 10, 1945; [Sections looking to front, rear and sides.] (Flatfile 2004.IA.13-1)
    - "Getty 1st Floor, John Byers, architect,", April 10, 1946; [Photocopies of Ranch House Blueprints.] (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-5)
    - "Getty 2nd Floor, John Byers, architect,", April 10, 1946; [Photocopies of Ranch House Blueprints.] (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-5)
    - "Getty Job – interior elevations. John Byers, Architect,", May 22, 1946 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-1)
    - "Cem. Frame at Bronze Door – Getty Job. John Byers, Architect,", undated (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-4)
    - [Unspecified blueprint], undated; ["46" on verso. Wall elevation.] (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-4)
    - "Mrs. Getty's Bedroom. John Byers Architect", undated; ["48" on verso.] (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-4)
    - "Section at Stairs. John Byers, Architect,", May 22, 1946; ["42" on verso.] (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-4)
    - "Footing and Slab Detail – Getty Job. John Byers, Architect,", undated; ["44 on verso.] (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-4)
    - "Getty job theatre proscenium,", July 13, 1946 (Flatfile 2004.IA.13-2)
    - "Getty job roof plan, John Byers, Architect,", July 18, 1946 (Flatfile 2004.IA.13-2)
    - "Bay plan – Mrs. Getty BR [bedroom]. John Byers, Architect,", July 23, 1946 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-3)
    - "Getty Job, Schedule Exterior Opening,", August 1, 1946 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-3)
      [Possibly John Byers.]
    - "Getty Job – Marble Stairs and Iron Handrails. John Byers, Architect,", August 14, 1946 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-3)
    - [Drawing on vellum], undated (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-3)
      [Possibly John Byers. Depicts a small cabinet.]
    - "[Untitled], John Byers,", 1946 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-3)
      [Ranch House ground floor plan.]
    - [Unlabeled], 1946; [With pencil notations, similar handwriting to John Byers drawings. Possibly a wall elevation.] (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-3)
    - [Unlabeled], undated; [With pencil notations (small), similar handwriting to John Byers drawings. Unidentified room floor plan.] (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-3)
    - "Residence for Mr. and Mrs. J. Paul Getty and family, Second floor plan, John Byers, Architect,", August 6, 1946 (Flatfile 2004.IA.13-1)
    - "Getty Job – window elevations. John Byers, Architect,", August 29, 1946 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-1)
    - "Getty Job. John Byers, architect,", August 29, 1946 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-2)
      [Window specifications.]
    - "Getty job. Cellar plan, John Byers, Architect,", October 11, 1946 (Flatfile 2004.IA.13-2)
    - "Residence Shutters. Getty Job. John Byers, architect,", December 2, 1946 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-1)
    - "Getty 1st floor. John Byers, Architect,", 1946 (Flatfile 2004.IA.13-2)
    - "Getty 2nd floor. John Byers, Architect,", 1946 (Flatfile 2004.IA.13-2)
    - "Alternate plan, Second fl. Bath, Getty job,", undated (Flatfile 2004.IA.13-2)
    - "Mr. Paul Getty, California, Plan of the Art Gallery. 2nd floor for building, cornice and alterations,", undated (Flatfile 2004.IA.13-2)
    - "Kalamein Bronze Doors – Getty", circa 1946 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-1)
      [Probably John Byers.]
    - "Door and Window details, Owner's Bedroom, Getty Job. John Byers, architect,", circa 1946; [2 blueprints.] (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-1)
    - "Bear Pit and Wolf Run – sheet 1 of 1. John Byers, architect. Parker, Zehnder and Associates, construction engineers,", September 3, 1946; [2 copies.] (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-2)
    - "Bear Pit and Wolf Run – Plot Plan – sheet 2 of 2. Parker, Zehnder and Associates,", September 18, 1946; [2 copies.] (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-2)
    - "Getty At Bronze Door,", undated (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-8C)
    - "Tablet at Art Gallery – Getty Job – Roosevelt Highway" John Byers, architect, March 26, 1947 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-8C)
    - [Untitled], undated (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-8C)
    - "Getty Terrace. John E. Mackel, Structural Engineer,", May 1947 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-5)
  - Starling Watson renovations:
    - "Plan, Elevation and Sections Retaining Walls. Living Room Terrace for Mr. Paul Getty Residence, Starling Watson,", June 3, 1947 (Flatfile 2004.IA.13-2)
    - "Dressing Room – Mrs. Getty's – 17900 Roosevelt Highway. The office of Starling Watson,", October 16, 1947; [2 prints. Profiles of molds; elevation plan and details.] (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-5)
  - "Getty Estate Court and Walls. Macco Corporation, Parker Zehnder and Assoc. Engineers,", March 31, 1948 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-5)
  - Lighting plans:
    - "J. Paul Getty – Detail of Proposed Cove Lighting. Wendel Western, Inc.,", April 29, 1948 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-5)
    - "J. Paul Getty – Detail of Proposed Cove Lighting. Wendel Western, Inc.,", April 29, 1948; [With pencil annotations.] (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-5)
    - "Details for fountain illumination. Wendell Western, Inc.,", May 1948 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-5)
  - Art gallery renovation:
    - "Art Gallery Mr. Paul Getty – Room Louis XVI – 2nd Floor,", 1950 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-7)
    - "Monsieur Getty Art Gallery,", circa 1950 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-7)
    - "Art Gallery Mr. Paul Getty 1st Floor,", October 20, 1950 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-8)
    - "Art Gallery Mr. Paul Getty, First Floor – Return of String Board on Landing,", November 11, 1950 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-8)
    - "Art Gallery Mr. Paul Getty. Los Angeles, Calif. Face Pan Coupe,", November 20, 1950 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-9)
    - "Art Gallery Mr. Paul Getty. Los Angeles, Calif. Detail B Retour Du Limon Sur Le Palier. / Detail A. Coupe Sur Le Limon,", November 20, 1950 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-9)
    - "Art Gallery J. Paul Getty, Los Angeles California, Face Grande Tapisserie,", November 21, 1950 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-7)
    - "Art Gallery J. Paul Getty, Los Angeles California, Plan,", November 21, 1950 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-7)
    - "Art Gallery Monsieur Getty. Tapestry View,", 1950 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-7)
    - "Art Gallery Monsieur Getty. Piece Louis XVI no. 2 2nd floor,", 1950 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-7)
    - "Monsieur Getty Art Gallery. 1st Floor,", circa 1950; [4 torn pieces.] (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-9)
    - "Mr. Paul Getty, Santa Monica, First Floor Room, Elevation Facing Stairs. Jensen Inc.,", December 12, 1950 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-6)
    - "Mr. Paul Getty, Santa Monica, First Floor Room, Entrance Elevation. Jensen Inc.,", December 12, 1950 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-6)
    - "Mr. Paul Getty, Santa Monica, First Floor Room, Elevation Facing Entrance. Jensen Inc.,", December 12, 1950 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-6)
    - "Art Gallery Mr. Paul Getty—Elevation C,", December 13, 1950; ["43" on verso.] (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-9)
    - "Art Gallery Monsieur Paul Getty. Los Angeles, Calif. Room - Louis XVI - 2nd Floor,", December 27, 1950 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-9)
    - "Monsieur Paul Getty, Louis XVI Room, First Floor,", December 27, 1950 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-8)
    - "Monsieur Paul Getty 2nd Floor. Depart Escalier,", December 27, 1950 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-8)
    - "Mr. Paul Getty, Santa Monica Art Gallery, 1st floor. Plans Showing the Modification of the Stripe around the flooring. Jensen Inc., New York,", February 28, 1951 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-6)
    - "Art Gallery Mr. Paul Getty. Los Angeles, Calif. Room. Louis XVI. 2nd Floor,", March 1, 1951 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-9)
    - "Mr. Paul Getty – Details of tapestries, stretchers. Jensen Inc.,", March 2, 1951 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-6)
    - "Mr. Paul Getty, Santa Monica. 1st floor plan. Plan for Wendel Lighting,", April 20, 1951 (Flatfile 2004.IA.13-2)
    - "Mr. Paul Getty, Santa Monica. 2nd floor room. Plan for Wendel Lighting,", April 23, 1951 (Flatfile 2004.IA.13-2)
    - "Mr. Paul Getty, 3rd Floor Room, Jensen, Inc.,", April 24, 1951 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-6)